JESSICA HUA

773-510-5953 * jessicahua95@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/jessicahua * www.github.com/jessicahua95

CAREER OBJECTIVE

I am an undergraduate senior pursuing a B.S. in Computer Science with a minor in Organizational Communication. The combination of my expertise is unique having completed several technical projects as well as experience in leadership, management, recruitment, and consulting.

TECHNICAL SUMMARY

- Languages: Java, Python, C, UML
- Databases: Oracle SQL
- Applications: IntelliJ, Eclipse, SQL Developer, Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Adobe Photoshop/Illustrator, Dreamweaver
- Platforms: Windows, Unix, Ubuntu, Raspberry Pi

EDUCATION

DePaul University, Chicago, IL

Bachelor of Science: Computer Science (Software Engineering), Minor: Organizational Communication Expected: June 2017, Cumulative GPA: 3.5

- Object-Oriented Software Development
- Database Programming
- Data Structures in Java I & II
- Technical Writing

- Small Group Communication
- Leadership and Team Building
- Communication Consulting
- Employment Interviewing

PROJECTS

Logistic Application – November 2016

• Drawing from Object-Oriented Principles and Design Patterns, developed a java application that will manage facilities, items, and transportation to perform order processing, update inventories, generate reports. This includes parsing in XML files.

Movie Rental Database – November 2015

• In Oracle SQL, used PL/SQL blocks, triggers and cursors to develop a database for a video shop to keep track of customers and rentals. Code includes functions such as customer registration, update expiration date, video search, video checkout, video return and customers' unreturned videos.

<u>Attendance/Data Spreadsheet</u> – January 2015

 Created a multi-functional excel sheet to keep track of the roster, mark attendance for events, and calculate points rewarded for events attended.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

National MS Society, Chicago, IL

Leadership Events Intern, February 2017 – Present

- Utilize my communication skills to reach out to individuals to recruit volunteers for events.
- Use Adobe Photoshop to create graphics to market events.

Adidas, Chicago, IL

Cash Wrap Supervisor, September 2015 – Present

- Approve returns, exchanges, discounts, customer coupons, and employee sales.
- Train employees on cash wrap policies and cash wrap procedures such as how to process sales, returns and exchanges.
- Coordinate visual merchandising for new campaign launches and markdowns.
- Utilize problem solving skills to handle any customer complaints and assure they leave with satisfaction.

Phi Sigma Pi National Honor Fraternity, Eta Gamma Chapter, DePaul University

Founding Brother and Secretary, January 2015 – June 2016

- Take minutes to record all proceedings and submit all required documentation to Nation Headquarters.
- Utilize Excel to keep track of member roster, attendance for events, and point system to assure all requirements are met.
- Manage calendar and oversee committees to assure that planning for events are on schedule.
- Send weekly updates via email to all members to highlight important announcements and upcoming events.
- Transition new executive board members and committee chairs into their role through training.

ORGANIZATIONS

- Phi Sigma Pi National Honor Fraternity Eta Gamma Chapter
- Phi Mu Fraternity Rho Mu Chapter

April 2014 - Present

September 2014 - Present